surveymethods.com 2019-02-04

# Privacy Policy | SurveyMethods

We’ve updated our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use to be in compliance with the **European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** , effective from May 25, 2018. These updates govern the use and access of the SurveyMethods website and its services. Please review and understand our updated policies and terms carefully.

**This Privacy Policy is effective from May 21, 2018 for new and existing users.**

One of SurveyMethods’ top priorities is preserving the privacy and security of data of our Registered Users, End Users, and Visitors. We collect only as much data as needed to make the SurveyMethods experience secure, efficient, and successful.

This Privacy Policy governs how SurveyMethods collects and uses data from its Registered Users, End Users, and Visitors.

**For the purpose of this Policy:**

“SurveyMethods” refers to SurveyMethods, Inc. and the online services (“Service”) provided to you by SurveyMethods, Inc. through its website [https://surveymethods.com](https://surveymethods.com/).

**“Registered Users”** refer to individuals or organizations subscribing to our Services by registering for an account with SurveyMethods.

**“End Users”** refer to the audience for a SurveyMethods survey, poll, or a newsletter. They may provide responses to a survey, poll, or view and interact with a newsletter.

**“Visitors”** refer to those who visit the SurveyMethods website. They may browse through the website, and may contact SurveyMethods using an online form.

## **1. What Data does SurveyMethods Collect and how is It Used? **

### **1.1 Registered Users**

  * We collect and store one or more of the following: your email address, password, first name, last name, job function, company name, phone, billing address, country, state/province/region, city, zip/postal code, and very limited credit card details (the cardholder’s name, only the last 4 digits of the credit card number, and the expiration date) for authentication. We do not store the CVV number.
  * We use this data to provide you with customer support and other services, bill you for our services, collect feedback, send you account-related notifications, and keep you informed about our key features, important feature updates, and latest releases.
  * We store data related to your surveys, polls, and newsletters in your account that you access using your login-id and password. This includes questions, responses, images, email lists, data you enter while configuring or customizing any settings, etc. This data is processed by SurveyMethods to enable you to perform functions like design and distribution of surveys, polls, newsletters, and analysis & reporting.
  * We do not share any personally identifiable and account-related data with a third party without your explicit consent. However, if you use the SurveyMethods API or 3rd Party Integrations, you will need to share your SurveyMethods login-id and the “API Key” with the 3rd party for authentication. For more on our API Terms of Use, click here.
  * We may display your organization’s name and/or logo on our customer listing (unless agreed upon otherwise by both parties herein).
  * Your data will visible to those with whom you share your published reports or extracted data/reports.
  * If you collaborate your surveys with other Registered Users, all collaborated data and your login-id will be visible to them.
  * If you have an Enterprise Account, the Enterprise Master Account (Administrator) will be able to see the SurveyMethods login-id, first name, last name, phone number, account type, and expiration date of the Enterprise Child Accounts (Member Accounts). The Enterprise Child Accounts can view the SurveyMethods login-id, first name, last name, phone number, job title, job function, country, state/province/region, and city of the Enterprise Master Account.
  * When you access SurveyMethods, we collect your IP address, browser type, device type, operating system and its version, data about the pages that were accessed, and timestamps. We use this data to: 
    * Troubleshoot problems and fix bugs (issues).
    * Ensure website compatibility across different devices and browsers.
    * Identify trends and patterns in the usage of our Services.
    * Gain insights for adding or improving the functionality and usability of our website.
    * Monitor and prevent abuse.
  * To prevent any undesirable, abusive, or illegal activities, we have automated processes in place that check your data for malicious activities, spam, and fraud.
  * We may use your data if required by law, court orders, subpoenas, or to enforce our agreements.
  * We collect information using cookies. Cookies are digital files that allow websites to recognize returning users. While most browsers allow users to refuse cookies or request permission on a case-by-case basis, our site will not function properly without them. SurveyMethods uses cookies primarily to enable the smooth functioning of its Services.
  * While accessing SurveyMethods, you may be able to access links that take you to websites external to SurveyMethods. SurveyMethods is not responsible for the content, policies, or terms of these websites.

### **1.2 End Users**

End User data refers to data that is collected by:

    * SurveyMethods’ Surveys and Polls
    * Newsletters from SurveyMethods
  * When responding to a survey or a poll, End Users may provide personal data such as first name, last name, phone number, email address, demographic data like age, date of birth, gender, education, income, marital status, and any other sensitive data that directly or indirectly identifies them. SurveyMethods does not use or share any data of End Users in any way. The Registered User is solely responsible for ensuring that collection and sharing of any End User data, personal or otherwise, is done with the End User’s consent and in accordance with applicable data protection laws.
  * Since the Registered User controls and manages all data of their surveys, polls, and newsletters, End Users may contact the Registered User for any concerns regarding consent, privacy and protection of their data, or if they wish to access, modify, or delete their data.
  * When you access surveys, polls, or newsletters, SurveyMethods collects your IP address, browser type, device type, operating system and its version, data about the pages that were accessed, and timestamps. We use this data to: 
    * Troubleshoot problems and fix bugs (issues).
    * Ensure website compatibility across different devices and browsers.
    * Monitor and prevent abuse.
  * To prevent any undesirable, abusive, or illegal activities, we have automated processes in place that check your data for malicious activities, spam, and fraud.
  * We may use your data if required by law, court orders, subpoenas, or to enforce our agreements.
  * We collect information using cookies. Cookies are digital files that allow websites to recognize returning users. While most browsers allow users to refuse cookies or request permission on a case-by-case basis, our site will not function properly without them. SurveyMethods uses cookies primarily to enable the smooth functioning of its Services.
  * While accessing SurveyMethods, you may be able to access links that take you to websites external to SurveyMethods. SurveyMethods is not responsible for the content, policies, or terms of these websites.

### **1.3 Visitors**

  * SurveyMethods may record your personal data (such as your name, email address, phone, company, and the reason you are contacting us) when you visit the SurveyMethods website and contact us using our online form. Any consent for the collection and use of your data in this case is entirely voluntary.
  * When you browse through the SurveyMethods website or submit the online form, SurveyMethods collects your IP address, browser type, device type, operating system and its version, data about the pages that were accessed, and timestamps. We use this data to: 
    * Troubleshoot problems and fix bugs (issues).
    * Ensure website compatibility across different devices and browsers.
    * Monitor and prevent abuse.
  * We may use your contact information to respond to you. We do not share any personally identifiable information with a third party without your explicit consent.
  * To prevent any undesirable, abusive, or illegal activities, we have automated processes in place that check your data for malicious activities, spam, and fraud.
  * We may use your data if required by law, court orders, subpoenas, or to enforce our agreements.
  * We collect information using cookies. Cookies are digital files that allow websites to recognize returning users. While most browsers allow users to refuse cookies or request permission on a case-by-case basis, our site will not function properly without them. SurveyMethods uses cookies primarily to enable the smooth functioning of its Services.
  * While accessing SurveyMethods, you may be able to access links that take you to websites external to SurveyMethods. SurveyMethods is not responsible for the content, policies, or terms of these websites.

## **2. The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

_“The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaces the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and was designed to harmonize data privacy laws across Europe, to protect and empower all EU citizens’ data privacy and to reshape the way organizations across the region approach data privacy.”_

The GDPR is effective from May 25, 2018, and applies to all organizations collecting, storing, and processing personal data of data subjects residing in the EU. 

The GDPR defines Data Subject and Personal Data as the following:

  * **Data Subject:** A natural person whose personal data is processed by a Controller or Processor.
  * **Personal Data:** Any information related to a natural person or ‘Data Subject’, that can be used to directly or indirectly identify the person.

[Click here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/) to know about all the key changes related to the GDPR.  

## **3. Data Controller and Processor**

The GDPR defines Data Controller and Data Processor as the following:

  * **Data Controller:** The entity that determines the purposes, conditions and means of the processing of personal data.
  * **Data Processor:** The entity that processes data on behalf of the Data Controller.

In context to the above definitions as defined in the GDPR, SurveyMethods acts both as a Processor and Controller of the personal data of data subjects.

### **3.1 SurveyMethods’ Roles and Responsibilities**

As a Registered User, when you enter into an agreement with SurveyMethods for using the SurveyMethods Services, SurveyMethods will be the Controller of your data. See the section Registered Users.

For Visitor Data, SurveyMethods will act both as a Controller and Processor. See the section Visitors.

SurveyMethods is responsible for the safety of personal data of its data subjects, which remains our top priority. All data is stored in secure facilities with strict access control and round-the-clock monitoring.

In the event of a confirmed data breach, SurveyMethods will promptly notify its Registered Users, who will be the point persons for any communication related to the breach. The Registered Users shall be kept informed about the status and result of the inquiry at all stages and the corrective actions being taken.

### **3.2 Registered Users’ Roles and Responsibilities**

For End User data, the Registered User will be the Controller and SurveyMethods will be the Processor. See the section End Users.

  * As a Registered User and the Data Controller, you need to **take the consent of your data subjects** when collecting personal data and sending emails.
  * Ensure that your **data subjects understand unambiguously the consent** they are giving.
  * Make sure you **inform** **your data subjects** when collecting personal data, the reasons you are collecting the data, and what are you going to do with the data.

## **4. Data Subjects’ Rights**

  * **Right to be informed** : The data subject shall have the right to be informed about the collection and use of their personal data in a concise, transparent, intelligible, and easily accessible form, using clear and plain language.
  * **Right to access** : The data subject shall have the right to access their personal data.
  * **Right to restrict processing** : The data subject shall have right to restrict the processing of their personal data if they contest the accuracy of their personal data, or the data has been unlawfully processed.
  * **Right to rectification** : The data subject shall have the right to request the Data Controller for rectification of inaccurate personal data or completion of incomplete personal data without undue delay.
  * **Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)** : The data subject shall have the right to have their personal data erased without undue delay.
  * **Right to object to processing** : At any time, the data subject can object to the processing of their personal data on grounds relating to their particular situation.
  * **Right to withdraw consent** : The data subject shall have the right to withdraw their consent at any time.
  * **Right to data portability** : The data subject shall have the right to receive their personal data, which they have provided to a Controller, in a structured, commonly used, and machine readable format.

[Click here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/) for a more detailed insight into the rights of data subjects, as outlined in the GDPR.  

If you have any questions or concerns, or have any requests to exercise any of the above rights, please [contact us](https://app.surveymethods.com/contact/pp/).

## **5. Data Deletion and Retention**

As a Registered User of SurveyMethods, you are responsible for your data and its retention. SurveyMethods does not delete the data in your SurveyMethods account. End Users will need to ask the Registered User for any information on their data and how long their survey responses and data would be stored in the SurveyMethods system. Registered Users who wish to delete their account permanently can [contact us](https://app.surveymethods.com/contact/pp/).

## **6. Data Backup**

SurveyMethods performs regular data backups. The backups are maintained for a maximum of 30 days, after which they are deleted.

## **7. Opting Out**

SurveyMethods allows individuals to opt out of sales and marketing communication from us at any time. However, Registered Users are required to receive communication limited to system feature notifications and periodic system update notifications.

## **8. Acceptance**

**This Privacy Policy is effective from May 21, 2018 for new and existing users.** SurveyMethods’ Registered Users, End Users, and Visitors should carefully read and agree to our Privacy Policy, otherwise they may not use the SurveyMethods website and its Services.

SurveyMethods reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this policy that may affect the way we collect or use your data will be notified on the SurveyMethods website. By using or accessing SurveyMethods and its Services following any such changes, you confirm your agreement to such changes or revisions.

This Privacy Policy is an integral part of the Terms and Conditions of use of the SurveyMethods website.
